{
    "id": "ee3eaab96f0d4cdeb34160b47cc30ba0",
    "title": "Intermediate Level Grammar Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "It is …………………………… dark that I cannot see anything.",
            "description": "We use so...that... to indicate cause and effect. ",
            "answers": [
                "very",
                "too",
                "so"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "He is …………………………… to understand this.",
            "description": "Enough shows sufficiency. It goes after the adjective or adverb modified by it. ",
            "answers": [
                "so clever",
                "too clever",
                "clever enough"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "What a charming girl ………………………….!",
            "description": "In exclamations we do not use inversion. That means the subject goes before the verb.",
            "answers": [
                "is she",
                "she is"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "She is ………………………… young to go to school.",
            "description": "Note the pattern too..to...",
            "answers": [
                "so",
                "very",
                "too",
                "enough"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "How ………………………….. the holiday has passed!",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "quick",
                "quickly"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "If you hurt the dog, it …………………………….. you.",
            "description": "In the first conditional, use a simple present tense in the if clause and will + first form of the verb in the main clause. ",
            "answers": [
                "will bite",
                "bites",
                "would bite"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "If I had gone to university, I …………………………… a better job.",
            "description": "In the third conditional, we use a past perfect tense in the if-clause and would/could/might + have + past participle in the main clause. ",
            "answers": [
                "can find",
                "could find",
                "could have found"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "If you were a billionaire, how ……………………………. you spend your time?",
            "description": "In the second conditional, we use a simple past in the if-clause and would + first form of the verb in the main clause. ",
            "answers": [
                "will",
                "can",
                "would"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "If you had left that wasp alone, it …………………………………… you.",
            "description": "In the third conditional, we use a past perfect tense in the if-clause and would/could/might + have + past participle in the main clause. ",
            "answers": [
                "will not sting",
                "would not sting",
                "would not have stung"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "It is no good ……………………………… to her.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "to talk",
                "talking"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "It was careless …………………………… her to make that mistake.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "with",
                "of",
                "for"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "It is wicked ………………………….. him to say such things.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "for",
                "of",
                "with"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        }
    ]
}